嘿嘿，星期六不许
Hey hey,
we don't have to have
开牛仔会
this cowboy party
on Saturday.
看我拿剪子把你们的生日
从日历上挖掉
I'II get my scissors and cut your
birthday right out of the caIendar.
哦，拜托！
Oh, come on!
没准是推销波本威士忌的
Maybe this is
a bourbon saIesman.
- 妈，嗨。哦我的天
- 嗨
- Mom, hi. Oh my gosh.
- Hi.
你知道，你来早了。
生日聚会只开一天
You know, you're earIy.
The birthday party's not for two days.
不，我知道。
我今天过来是有事跟你说
No, I know. I came today
because I wanted to taIk to you.
- 你怎么不打电话？
- 你爸和我分开了
- But why didn't you caII?
- Your father and I have separated.
哈喽，露易斯
HeIIo, Lois.
- 嗨，玛丽
- 我看到你开车来
- Hi, Marie.
- I saw you drive up.
我得到的聚会时间是错的？
Was I given the wrong day
for the party?
怎么了？
What?
什么事？
What's going on?
我错过什么了吗？
Did I miss something?
- 我想我错过什么了
- 没事的
- I think I missed something.
- It's okay.
- 一会见，好吗，玛丽？
- 我想我错过什么了
- We'II see you Iater, okay, Marie?
- I think I missed something.
如果有人有话跟我说，
我就在街对面
If anybody needs to taIk to me,
I'm just right across the street.
我做了香草巧克力蛋糕
I have marbIe cake!
你说什么？
What are you
taIking about?
什么叫你们分开了？
What do you mean
you've separated?
唔，我不认为我和你父亲之间
WeII, I don't suppose
it's any secret
出了问题是什么秘密
that your father and I
have had our probIems.
我们甚至还试了新泽西的
婚姻咨询
We even tried that marriage counseIing
thing in New Jersey.
咨询了一星期就这么个结果？
One week of counseIing and this is
what you come up with?
你们就是这么解决问题的？
This is how
you work things out?
哦，亲爱的，
这不可能是完全的惊人的
Oh, honey, this can't be
a compIete surprise.
你知道我们从不是
真的合得来
You know we were never
truIy compatibIe
而新泽西事实上
让我们明白了这点
and New Jersey actuaIIy
made us see that.
哦，是啊，没错，
新泽西，
Oh, yeah, that's right,
New Jersey,
“撒手放弃的州”
''The Just Give Up State.''
唔，41年了，
WeII, it was 41 years,
所以你不能说我们
没有努力
so you can't say we didn't
give it a shot.
现在请不要难过了，
Now pIease,
don't be upset,
因为我就不，真的
because I'm not, reaIIy.
我觉得美妙而自由
I feeI wonderfuI
and free.
你真难以置信。
那爸爸呢？
You're unbeIievabIe.
And what about Dad?
唔，他也没事，
并且我们会保持亲近的
WeII, he's fine too,
and we'II stay cIose.
也许能成为
比以前更好的朋友
We'II probabIy be
better friends than before.
你知道帕特和希瑞尔
也经过这个，
And you know Pat and CyriI
went through this,
他们现在快乐多了
and they're much
happier now.
他们共有狗的监护权
They share custody
of the dogs.
这太像你了，知道吗？
This is just Iike you,
you know?
你时髦和赶潮流
的生活方式
Your hip
and trendy IifestyIe.
现在兴分居了，
所以你们就做这个
It's chic to get separated now,
so that's what you do
不投入任何努力――
instead of putting
any effort into--
别这样，黛比拉，
这可不公平了
Come on, Debra,
now that's not fair.
除了努力没别的了，
我试了
It's been nothing but effort,
and I have tried.
你试的东西
You have never tried
anything for Ionger
从没长过杂志封面
than it was
on a magazine cover.
玛丽
Marie.
哈喽？
HeIIo?
你好呀，露易丝
Hiya, Lois.
我来找玛丽
I was Iooking
for Marie.
哦，是吗？对我来说，
刚好相反
Oh, yeah? For me,
just the opposite.
果汁？
Juice?
不，谢谢
No, thank you.
你介意我在这待上一会吗？
WouId you mind if I
just hung out here for a bit?
什么也没发生
Nothing's going on.
你是什么？
What are you?
穿上点衣服，
家里有客人
Put on some cIothes
with company in the house.
什么客人？
她是家里人
What company?
She's famiIy.
嘿，又没什么是她没在
华伦身上见到过的
Hey, there's nothing here
she ain't seen on Warren.
我说错了吗？
Am I wrong?
嘿，华伦哪去了？
阿布达比（阿联酋首府）还是哪？
Hey, where is Warren?
Abu Dhabi or something?
可能的
CouId be.
我来就是为这事
That's why
I came over.
我想告诉你们
I want
to teII you that
华伦和我分开了
Warren and I
are spIitting up.
我去穿裤子
I'II put pants on.
哦
Oh.
小可怜
You poor dear.
不不，没事的，
玛丽
No no, it's okay,
Marie.
没事的
It's okay.
他要离开你了
He's Ieaving you.
不，这完全是相互的
No, it's compIeteIy
mutuaI.
我们都很开心，说实话
We're both
quite happy, honestIy.
你不用在我面前掩饰
You don't have to
pretend with me.
你可以告诉我
所有糟糕的细节
You can teII me
aII the awfuI detaiIs.
求你了
PIease.
不，不要穿那条裤子。
这条要捐到美丽心愿（慈善机构）
No, not those pants.
They go to GoodwiII.
嘿，我喜欢这条裤子
Hey, I Iove these pants.
你凭什么送去美丽心愿？！
Who the heII are you
to give 'em to GoodwiII?!
屁股上有洞！
你都穿透了！
There are hoIes in the seat!
You've worn through them!
那你就不能把它送去美丽心愿！
那是坏心愿！
Then you can't give 'em to GoodwiII!
That's bad wiII!
干衣机里还有其他的裤子。
随便拿条穿上
There are other pants in the dryer.
Put on one of those.
不！这就是我要的裤子！
No! These are the pants!
不，你不能穿这条裤子，
弗兰克！
No, you are not wearing
those pants, Frank!
- 你就像是野兽！
- 野兽根本都不喜欢裤子！
- You're just Iike an animaI!
- AnimaIs don't even Iike pants!
- 你故意的！
- 我没有！
- You did that on purpose!
- I did not!
你才是野兽！
You're the animaI!
继续，亲爱的
Go on, dear.
嘿！奶酪小傻傻
Hey! Cheese doodIe.
我给孩子们星期六
的聚会订了充气跳跳房
I ordered a moon bounce
for the kids party Saturday.
是个畜栏。
刚好配合牛仔的主题
It's a corraI.
Goes with your whoIe cowboy theme.
他们说只有80磅
以下的才可以跳
They said you gotta be
under 80 pounds to jump in there,
不过让他去死好了。
我是要跳的
but screw that guy.
I'm going in.
听着，雷
Listen, Ray.
- 什么？
- 我有事告诉你
- What?
- I have to teII you something.
好吧
Yeah.
很严重
It's pretty big.
哦，天
Oh, boy.
是啊
Yeah.
我父母分居了
My parents
have separated.
他们在走离婚的路
They're on the path
to divorce.
- 你还笑？你还笑？
- 不不不不。不！
- You Iaugh? You Iaugh?!
- No no no no. No!
只是有那么一刻，知道吗？
It's one of those
moments, you know?
太严肃了还是怎么的
It's too serious
or something.
我没准备好
I wasn't ready
for it.
这太糟了
This is terribIe.
不，好了，
No, aII right, st--
没什么可笑的
There's nothing
funny here.
这太可怕了。
你知道是为什么吗？
This is awfuI.
You know what it is.
只是――只是你说的方式
It's just-- it's the way
that you said it.
“他们在走离婚的路”
''They're on the path
to divorce.''
我不是笑。我没有笑。
我没笑
I'm not smiIing. I didn't smiIe.
I'm not smiIing.
你知道为什么吗？
是我想象的画面
You know what it is?
It's the image I have.
我看到森林里一条小路，
I picture that there was
a path in the forest
然后一个木牌子上写着：
“离婚走这边”然后――
with, Iike, one of those wooden signs.
''Divorce this way'' and--
我不知道。什么？
I don't know. What?
――好像
“三只小猪，走这边”
--Iike ''Three IittIe pigs
this way.''
然后你说的时候的脸色，
And then your face
when you said it,
只是那有点严肃。
就是这样
it was just a IittIe serious.
That's aII.
不！
No!
我想我今天上班太开心了
I think I had too much
fun at work today.
你知道贩售机怎么了？
贩售机的门，
You know what happened?
The door to the vending machine,
坏掉了，明白了？
it was broken, see?
免费的糖果
Free candy.
这是我最喜欢的
These are my favorites.
Twix（威化饼）
Twix.
嘿
Hey.
饿了？
Hungry?
你知道，你要是有兴趣，
You know,
if you're interested,
我楼上还有点糖果
I got a IittIe candy
Ieft upstairs.
没事，我还有糖果
It's okay,
I got my candy.
你父母怎么了？
What happened
to your parents?
干嘛，你还没笑够？
Why, you want
another good Iaugh?
我没笑
I didn't Iaugh.
对不起
I'm sorry.
对不起。别这样，很遗憾你父母的事
I'm sorry. Come on, I'm sorry
about your parents.
这太糟了
It's very bad.
对不起。
咱们得谈谈这事
I'm sorry.
We have to taIk about this.
我想跟你谈谈这事
I wanna taIk
about this with you.
来吧，咱们谈谈
Come on, we have to
discuss this.
那么，你爸妈，
So, your parents,
乖乖……
boy...
- 说吧
- 唔，我不――
- Go ahead.
- WeII, I don't--
你能说什么呢？
我很遗憾
what do you say?
I'm sorry.
可是，我的意思是，
我得说
But, I mean,
I have to say this.
我想大家都能看出
这天会来的
I think everybody couId have seen
this coming, right?
我是说，还记得感恩节吧，
他们是怎么大喊大叫的？
I mean, remember Thanksgiving,
how they yeIIed?
这太可怕了。
我连派都要吃不下去了
It was terribIe.
I had a hard time finishing my pie.
我知道他们有问题，雷
I know they had
probIems, Ray.
那你怎么这么吃惊？
Then why are you
so surprised?
因为他们是我父母！
他们要分手了！
Because they're my parents!
They're spIitting up!
我不能相信的是
要离婚的是他们
What I can't beIieve is that
they're the ones getting a divorce.
应该是你父母才对
It shouId be your parents.
唔
WeII.
我不认为这是句友好的话
I don't think that's
a particuIarIy nice thing to say.
- 对不起
- 我想有人过分攀比了
- I'm sorry.
- I think someone's awfuIIy competitive.
好吧，对不起，雷
AII right,
I'm sorry, Ray.
不，没关系
No, that's fine.
关于我父母你想怎么说随便。
你平时也这样
Say what you want about my parents.
You usuaIIy do.
不过我要说的是
But I wiII say this.
也许，也许你父母分手是因为
Maybe, maybe your parents
are spIitting up
他们把事憋在心里太久，
because they kept
everything inside for so Iong
直到最后爆发
that they finaIIy
just expIoded.
就像你把布丁杯放进微波炉
Like when you put a pudding cup
in the microwave.
不是我干的，顺便说一句
Which was not me,
by the way.
这么说这不让你担心
So this doesn't
worry you?
- 什么？
- 咱们俩
- What?
- What about us.
- 什么意思？
- 要是咱们也变成那样呢？
- What do you mean?
- What if we're headed that way?
我也有很多事闷在心里
I keep a Iot
of stuff inside, too.
不，你没有
No, you don't.
我掉只袜子在地上，
I drop a sock
on the fIoor,
你叫得像恐怖片里一样
you scream Iike
a horror movie.
还有很多事我留在心里，
相信我
There's pIenty more I keep inside,
beIieve me.
不可能有太多的
There can't be
a Iot Ieft in there.
我恨我妈
I hate my mother.
不，你不恨。
你怎么知道是你妈的错？
No, you don't. How do you know
this is your mother's fauIt?
是她的错。
她太……
It's her fauIt.
She's so...
她为什么这么做？
Why is she doing this?
我是说，我父母在一起――
I mean, my parents
being together--
我的意思是，
我这辈子就靠着这个了
I mean, I have counted
on that my whoIe Iife.
从小学到大学，
Through schooI
and coIIege
然后是大学毕业后的奋斗，
and then struggIing
after coIIege,
你知道，当我不知道自己做的什么，
you know, when I didn't
know what I was doing
或者自己要去变成什么样，
至少我还有……
or where I was going,
at Ieast I had...
他们的婚姻就像是岩石，
Their marriage
was Iike a rock,
我的稳固的岩石
the one soIid rock
for me.
唔……
WeII...
也许那更像是个石头（结石），
好吗？
maybe it was more
Iike a stone, okay?
现在排出来了
And now it has passed.
- 够了。真的够了
- 我做什么了？
- That's enough. That's just enough.
- What did I do?
你就不能真正地谈话
You can't have
a reaI conversation.
- 你非得逗笑。白痴
- 那也不是那么好笑了！
- You gotta be funny. Idiot.
- It wasn't that funny!
嘿，不，别这样。
看，我想要理解你，好吗？
Hey, no, come on, Iook, I'm trying
to be understanding here, okay?
我可不是叫人白痴的人，
好吗？
I'm not the one who said ''idiot,''
aII right?
不过我愿意不去计较，
因为我理解
But I'm wiIIing to overIook it
because I understand.
你是个家庭破碎的小孩
You're the chiId
of a broken home.
- 哦，嗨
- 嗨
- Oh, hi.
- Hi.
爱丽的手帕破了
AIIy's kerchief tore.
是吗
Yeah.
唔，她需要另一条
WeII, she needs
another one to go
来配她的牛仔装扮
with her
cowgirI ensembIe.
好的，我去拿
Okay, I'II get it.
黛比拉，等等
Debra, wait.
什么？
What?
我不知道。
我只希望也许
I don't know.
I was just hoping that maybe
你过去两天能够
you couId have tried to come
to terms with the situation
- 试着接受现状
- 不，我没事，妈，
- over the Iast coupIe of days.
- No, I'm fine, Mom,
不过谢谢你给我
两天时间来接受
but thanks for the coupIe of days
to come to terms with it.
我得去拿手帕了
I gotta get
that kerchief.
别缠着我！
Leave me aIone!
别这样！
Come on!
咱们说过了的。
我是坏蛋
We said it before.
I'm the bad guy.
你说的。我没同意
You said that.
I did not agree to that.
唔，总不能有两个坏蛋吧，
好吗？
WeII, there can't
be two bad guys, okay?
- 这说不通
- 看，我想做坏蛋，好吗？
- That doesn't make sense.
- Look, I wanna be the bad guy, okay?
我总是好人。
我是警察
I'm aIways a good guy.
I'm a cop.
这太单调了
It's monotonous.
听着，胡子是我买的
Listen,
I bought the mustache.
是，唔，这是我孩子的聚会，好吗？
他们都恨好人
Yeah, weII, it's my kid's party, okay?
They aII hate the good guy.
那么你正需要点恨
So you couId use
a IittIe hate.
你知道吗？
You know what?
啊！
Aah!
丑恶雷蒙德来了！
It's Rotten Raymond!
他真有趣
He's so funny.
是的，他是好人
Yeah, he's a pip.
听着，我很遗憾听说你和华伦的事
Listen, I was sorry to hear
about you and Warren.
谢谢
Thank you.
我有过亲身经历
I've been there.
没错
That's right.
你妻子叫什么来的？
What was your wife's
name again?
乔安。实际上她很可怕
Joanne. She was actuaIIy
quite horribIe.
是的，我记得
Right, I remember.
告诉你吧，
时间会冲淡一切的
Just so you know,
it gets better as time passes.
知道吗？
You know?
谢谢，罗伯特
Thank you, Robert.
实际上，我们现在接受得很好
ActuaIIy, we're pretty
okay with it now.
是吗，乔安也一样
Yeah, so was Joanne.
她还办了聚会
She had a party.
- 哦？
- 在她原来的脱衣舞俱乐部
- Oh?
- At her oId strip cIub.
她的朋友都在那――
AII her friends
were there--
丝缎、泡泡、
Satin, BubbIes,
小舔舔
Lick-Lick.
人会犯错误
PeopIe make mistakes.
我会说她才是犯错误的人
I wouId say she's the one
that made the mistake.
谢谢
Thank you.
哦，听着
Oh, Iisten.
- 不，我只是想安慰你
- 祝你好运
- No, I was just trying to be consoIing.
- Good Iuck to you.
- 不，我不是想――
- 祝你好运！
- No, I didn't mean--
- Good Iuck to you!
对不起。
可他真的疯了
I'm sorry.
He reaIIy is crazy.
该死！愚蠢见鬼该死的东西
Damn it! Stupid damn
friggin' thing.
黛比拉
Debra.
你妈说你在上面
Your mom said
you were up here.
嗨，爸爸
Hi, Dad.
我找不到手帕了
I can't find a kerchief.
你在这干嘛？
What are you doing here?
唔，请柬上写的：
“大家来生日聚会了”
WeII, the invitation said
''Round 'em up birthday party.''
保证了有“嘈杂火热的时光”的
It promised a ''rootin' tootin' time.''
我真难过，爸爸
I'm so sorry, Dad.
是啊，我也是
Yeah, me, too.
对不起她这么对你
Sorry she's
doing this to you.
- 什么意思？
- 我知道她是什么样子
- What do you mean?
- I know how she is.
来，坐下
Here, sit down.
这不是你妈的错
This is not
your mother's fauIt.
- 别替她说话
- 听我说
- Don't you defend her.
- Listen to me.
我们都有一段时间不开心了
We have both been unhappy
- 你知道的
- 好吧，
- for some time now. You know that.
- AII right,
可你至少想要努力
but you're the one
who at Ieast tries to make an effort,
比如想去那个婚姻咨询
Iike wanting to go
to that marriage counseIing.
我能告诉你吗？
我从没真的想去新泽西
Can I teII you something? I never reaIIy
wanted to go to New Jersey.
你想知道我为什么选那吗？
You want to know
why I picked that pIace?
因为我想看到的是
Because I was
Iooking forward
你妈怎么恨那的
to how much your Mother
wouId hate it.
唔，她喜欢那里，
WeII, she Ioved it,
而我则闷的头骨都要裂开了
and I was the one bored
out of my freakin' skuII.
那些个讨论会――
Those workshops--
“升华你灵魂伴侣的灵魂”
''PoIishing your
souI mate's souI.''
所以……
So...
你真的不该怪你母亲，宝贝
You reaIIy mustn't bIame
your mother, honey.
是我说的结束了
I'm the one who actuaIIy
said it was over.
我不相信
I don't beIieve it.
- 是真的
- 她说了什么？
- It's true.
- And what did she say?
唔，她知道
WeII, she knew.
我们都知道
We both knew.
别哭，宝贝
Don't cry, honey.
我忍不住
I can't heIp it.
我是说，如果你们不是认真的，
I mean, why the heII
do you take vows
干嘛当初要发誓呢？
if they don't mean
anything?
我们那时是认真的
We meant it then.
你们小时候
我们也是认真的
We meant it
when you were kids.
可是当你和你姐姐去上大学，
But when your sister and then you
went off to coIIege,
就越来越难了
it kept getting harder.
唔，那亲来亲去、
一起旅行、
WeII, what about aII the kissing,
the traveIing together
车牌取名Pookums 1号2号
又是怎么回事？
and the Pookums 1 and 2
Iicense pIates?
这算什么？
What was that?
我知道，我知道
I know. I know.
我猜，到最后，
I guess, by the end,
大多数时候都是演戏
most of that was
just... a show.
而我们受够了
And we had enough.
我们俩都受够了
We both had enough.
不像雷的父母
It's not Iike
Ray's parents.
什么？
What?
他们好像掌握了个中奥秘
They seem
to have the secret.
什么？
What?
他们知道怎么做
They know how
to do it.
不用装门面
It's not a facade
for them.
可他们是疯子
But they're maniacs.
是的，但他们彼此真诚
Yes, but they're honest
with each other.
什么事都能敞开了说
Everything's out
in the open with them.
“蛋，玛丽，
别叨叨”
''Eggs, Marie,
and hoId the chatter.''
我喜欢那个
I Iove that.
我告诉你，
他们才是
I'II teII you,
they're the ones
该去作报告的人
who oughta be
giving the seminar.
你好呀
Howdy.
能把那个摘下来吗？
WouId you take
that off, pIease?
是，夫人
Yes, Ma'am.
觉得好些了吗？
FeeIing any better?
我猜是的
I guess.
真遗憾你的父母
Sorry about your parents.
我知道
I know.
可是你知道……
But you know...
咱们不会那样的
that's not us.
因为我――
'Cause I--
我想咱们差不多
什么事都说出来了
I think we kinda get
everything out in the open.
紧点
Tighter.
再紧些
你想我把胡子戴上吗？
You want me
to put on the mustache?
jojoba
yettoreturn@hotmail.com